<document>
<DOC>
<DOCNO>5000</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-CFBA3AF8FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>920602
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  02 JUN 92 / World Stock Markets (America): Growing optimism lifts Dow
Jones to record high
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By PATRICK HARVERSON
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   NEW YORK
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Wall Street
US STOCK MARKETS turned early weakness on higher bond yields into a
record-breaking performance yesterday as the Dow Jones Industrial Average
finished above 3,400 for the first time in its history, writes Patrick
Harverson in New York.
At the close the Dow was up 16.33 at 3,413.21, a near 40-point recovery from
its low of the early morning. Among other indices, the more broadly based
Standard &amp; Poor's 500 rose 1.93 to 417.25, the Amex composite rose 0.15 to
394.84 and the Nasdaq composite ended 3.21 higher at 588.37. Turnover on the
NYSE was 181m shares.
The dominant factor of the morning was bond prices, which fell almost a full
point at the long end (pushing the yield back up to nearly 8 per cent in the
process) as Treasury investors interpreted a strong May purchasing managers'
report as reducing the chances of another interest rate cut by the Federal
Reserve.
The selling in the equity markets, however, could not be sustained, and amid
growing enthusiasm about the outlook for the economy, share prices advanced
across all fronts late in the session.
The car sector led the way higher, with all three of the big car markers
rising as investors continued to anticipate a recovery in their fortunes.
General Motors rose Dollars 1 3/4 to Dollars 41 5/8 in turnover of 3.3m
shares, Ford added Dollars 1 7/8 at Dollars 46 3/8 in 2m shares, and
Chrysler advanced Dollars 1 3/4 to Dollars 19 3/4 as 1.9m shares changed
hands.
Chrysler received an additional boost from Salomon Brothers, the Wall Street
broking house, which raised its earnings outlook for the group and predicted
profits in both the second quarter and the full year 1992. Salomon set a new
price target for Chrysler stock of Dollars 25 over the next 12 months.
After the opening of trading was delayed because of an imbalance of orders
on the sell side, Commonwealth Edison fell Dollars 1 1/2 to Dollars 31 1/2
in the wake of a warning from the broking house, Kidder Peabody, that the
company's current divided rate might be cut.
Citicorp climbed Dollars  3/4 to Dollars 19 3/8 after Morgan Stanley
upgraded the stock from a 'hold' to a 'buy', citing dramatic strides in
cost-cutting, peaking problem real-estate assets in North America and an
expected boost to earnings from strong franchises in emerging markets.
Waste Management rose Dollars 2 3/8 to Dollars 38 in heavy trading on the
news that the Supreme Court had ruled in favour of the group's subsidiary
Chemical Waste Management, which had challenged a special fee levied by
Alabama on out-of-state hazardous waste.
Canada
TORONTO Stock prices closed higher in moderate trading. According to
preliminary data, the TSE 300 rose 16.05, or 0.47 per cent, to close at
3,403.98. Advancing issues edged declines 276 to 259.
Volume of 22.8m shares was up from Friday's 20.3m, and trading value rose to
CDollars 303.3m from CDollars 223.8m.
Eight of 14 stock groups closed higher, led by the transportation group, up
2.2 per cent.
Laidlaw B, the most-heavily weighted stock in the group, rose  3/8 to 12 1/4
. Financial services gained 1.5 per cent and gold was up 1.0 per cent.
Industrial products also closed higher.
Magna International A tumbled 1 1/8 to 32 5/8 . The company said it plans to
issue 3.2m class A shares at CDollars 32.25 a share.
</TEXT>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 41
</PAGE>
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO>5001</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-CFBA3AF7FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>920602
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  02 JUN 92 / Foreign Exchanges: Dollar rises on US indicators
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By JAMES BLITZ
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
THE DOLLAR staged a recovery in late European trading on the foreign
exchange markets yesterday following signs of strong US manufacturing growth
last month, writes James Blitz.
Potential dollar buyers grew confident after the National Association of
Purchasing Management's index rose at its fastest pace in almost four years
to stand at 56.3 in May from 51.3 the month before. The survey's employment
index also jumped to 49.1 from 43.9 in April, its highest level since April
1989. The dollar closed at DM1.6100 in London, after a previous close of
DM1.6070.
However, there was still uncertainty in a number of traders' minds about the
scope and pace of the US economic recovery. The April figures for personal
income and consumption released yesterday were both weaker than expected.
These showed a 0.1 per cent rise in personal income in April, and a 0.3 per
cent rise in consumption.
According to Mr Neil MacKinnon, chief economist at Yamaichi International in
London, yesterday's indicators may effectively add up to an ill omen. 'The
real danger is the mismatch in output gains and personal consumption,' he
says. 'If the increase in manufacturing output is not matched by personal
consumption there will be a build-up of stocks that will lead to a cut in
production in the third quarter.' Other economists believe that the market
needs more time to decide whether to invest in dollars. 'The market will
look at money supply figures on Thursday and the non-farm payroll on
Friday,' said Mr Nick Stamenkovic, an economist at DKB International in
London. 'Until we get signs of a stronger recovery the dollar will remain in
narrow ranges.'
Yesterday's good figures for business confidence in the US failed to
restrain the dollar's losses against the Japanese yen after the Bank of
Japan intervened to strengthen its currency for the fourth day running.
Analysts reckon that the BoJ has spent Dollars 500m in intervention
operations in the last four days, as it tries to reduce its huge trade
surplus in the run up to the summit of the Group of Seven leading industrial
nations in July. In late Asian trading, the BoJ pushed the dollar below
Y127, its lowest level for four months. By the end of the European trading
session, the dollar stood at Y127.40, after a previous close of Y127.70.
The Danish krone was well underpinned as the latest polls showed that Danes
will vote 'yes' in today's referendum on European economic and monetary
union. The krone remained at the foot of the European Monetary System's
grid, but at minus 34 per cent of allowed swing below its central Ecu rate,
after Friday's close of minus 37 per cent.
</TEXT>